A Guide to the Horace Edwards Gubernatorial Campaign Recordings, 1949
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Horace Edwards Gubernatorial Campaign Recordings, 1949
The Library of Virginia
43950
3 CD-Rs
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
For preservation purposes, patrons must use digital access copies.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Crown Collectibles, Chesterfield, Va., on 25 August 2008.
Alternative Form Available
Available in CD-R.
Biographical Information
Born in 1902 in Isle of Wight, Virginia, Horace Edwards began his political career shortly after his graduation from the University of Richmond in 1926 with a degree in law. In 1928 he worked on the presidential campaign of Al Smith. When Smith was defeated, Edwards returned to the practice of law but remained active in politics. In 1933 he was elected to the Virginia House of Delegates and served three terms. Appointed city attorney in 1938, Edwards held the position for ten years, guiding the city's direct annexation suits against Henrico and Chesterfield Counties.
Edwards was elected mayor of Richmond in 1946 and served for two years, resigning to seek the Democratic nomination for governor in the 1949 primary. During his unsuccessful campaign, Edwards spoke of more and better schools and better pay for teachers. In 1954 he accepted the position of Richmond city manager, a capacity in which he served for thirteen years. During his tenure, Richmond began several construction projects. Although Edwards later admitted that he ran his office often without a certain amount of diplomacy, he survived three attempts by the city council factions to oust him and became one of the city's most durable and effective administrators.
Following his resignation as city manager in 1967, Edwards was named as special counsel for the city in its annexation suit against Chesterfield County. He also continued his work with the National and Virginia Municipal Leagues and the law firm of Mays, Valentine, Davenport and Moore. Edwards suffered a stroke in 1985 and was hospitalized several times before his death on 27 January 1987.
Scope and Content
The Horace Edwards 1949 gubernatorial campaign collection consists of 3 CD-Rs created from 15 radio station transcription discs (.53 cu. ft and 1 box). The recordings include speeches given at election rallies by Edwards and his supporters, news reports about the campaign, as well as two recorded versions of his campaign song. His central campaign platform of state funding for public schools through an increase in the retail sales tax is documented.
Contents List
- Compact disc copies of radio transcription discs, 1949., Extent: 3 CD-Rs. (Box 1)
  Collection consists of 3 CD-Rs created from 15 radio station transcription discs. Files are listed chronologically.
  - Horace Edwards - WRNL Richmond, Va. (Part 1 of 2), 1949 March 14., Duration 13 min., 50 sec. (Disc 2, Track 3.)
  - Horace Edwards - WRNL Richmond, Va. (Part 2 of 2), 1949 March 14., Duration 14 min., 34 sec. (Disc 2, Track 4.)
  - Horace Edwards Campaign Song - WSVA Harrisonburg, Va., 1949 June 6., Duration 1 min., 35 sec. (Disc 1, Track 5.)
  - Horace Edwards Campaign Song - WSVA Harrisonburg, Va., 1949 June 6., Duration 3 min., 40 sec. (Disc 3, Track 2.)
  - Political News: Remote from Glen Roy - WRNL Richmond, Va., 1949 June 6., Duration 13 min., 57 sec. (Disc 2, Track 5.)
  - Horace Edwards Rally - WSVA Harrisonburg, Va. (Part 1 of 2), 1949 June 20., Duration 14 min., 04 sec. (Disc 3, Track 3.)
  - Horace Edwards Rally - WSVA Harrisonburg, Va. (Part 2 of 2), 1949 June 20., Duration 15 min., 00 sec. (Disc 3, Track 4.)
  - Address by Horace Edwards to Jaycee's Governor Rally - WDVA Danville, Va., 1949 June 24., Duration 16 min., 12 sec. (Disc 2, Track 2.)
  - Hughes and Bowden: Edwards for Governor - WRVA Richmond, Va., 1949 July 14., Duration 11 min., 52 sec. (Disc 1, Track 1.)
  - Horace Edwards for Governor speech by John Flannagan, 1949 July 20., Duration 6 min., 59 sec. (Disc 2, Track 1.)
  - Horace Edwards for Governor speeches by John Flannagan and Charles Moses, 1949 July 25., Duration 16 min., 54 sec. (Disc 1, Track 2.)
  - Horace Edwards for Governor Speech by Ashton Dovell (copy 1), 1949 July 28., Duration 14 min., 20 sec. (Disc 1, Track 3.)
  - Horace Edwards for Governor Speech by Ashton Dovell (copy 2), 1949 July 28., Duration 14 min., 14 sec. (Disc 1, Track 4)
  - WRVA News Review: Horace Edwards Bulletin - WRVA Richmond, Va., undated., Duration 13 min., 54 sec. (Disc 1, Track 6)
  - WRVA News Review: Horace Edwards Bulletin - WRVA Richmond, Va., undated., Duration 14 min., 23 sec. (Disc 3, Track 1)